KIRAN SIDDESHWAR

DETAILS

PHONE

+353 89499 8442

EMAIL

krnsddswr@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>Portfolio</u>

LinkedIn

SKILLS

Data Analysis

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Computational Sciences

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Machine Learning

• • • 0 0

Engineering Design

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

R programming

• • • • 0

Python

• • • 0 0

MS Excel

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

SOL

• • • 0 0

StarCCM+

• • • • 0

LANGUAGES

English

• • • • 0

German

• • 0 0 0

PROFILE

Highly analytical and innovative Engineer with extensive experience in Product Development, Data Analysis, and Engineering Design. Aiming to utilise 7 years of extensive experience, alongwith my Masters' knowledge to further my career in Product development and Data Analysis.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst, Mercedes-Benz R&D India

Bangalore

Nov 2016 — Aug 2019

Focus: Battery thermal management of EVs, Electronic Components' cooling analysis

- Performance analysis and function evaluation of battery cooling systems using design and numeric data.
- Recommended design changes consistently to be on par with market competition and maintained optimum performance along with production cost (maintained at 5% above lowest possible cost).
- Analysis of cooling concepts to maintain efficient working of the electronic components inside the cabin, using CFD and Exploratory Data analysis.
- Recommended design changes to maintain the optimum performance (on an average, 50% design change implementation was done on our analysis).

CAE Analyst, Mercedes-Benz R&D India

Bangalore

Nov 2013 — Oct 2016

Focus: Digital Sensor Positioning (DSP) for Mercedes-Benz prototypes

- Identified and compiled crucial test data from experimentation to be utilised by other stakeholders, which aided simulations and reduced testing (by 25%).
- Aided in increased digitalisation and automation in the Daimler shopfloor by introducing 3D-digital documents to visualise prototypes attached with sensors.
- Conducted training sessions and created instruction manuals for colleagues working in Germany to familiarise them with the technology and process.
- Established and secured DSP activities in India; widened the scope of the business to the Powertrain department (saved resources worth €500,000).

Design Engineer/Trainee, Mercedes-Benz R&D India

Bangalore

Jun 2012 — Oct 2013

Focus: Analysis of design concepts to select efficient vehicle layouts for Daimler Trucks

- Analysed different concept layout data for FUSO trucks and identified key packaging constraints in the "Future Truck" programme.
- Compiled crucial data enabling efficiency in segregation of vehicles based on homologation regulations.
- Provided crucial support to meet homologation regulations for the FUSO Asia-Pacific market.

EDUCATION

Masters' of Science, University College Dublin

Dublin

Sep 2019 — Aug 2020

2:1 Honours with GPA: 3.66

Topics: Predictive Analytics, Statistical Machine Learning, Multivariate Analysis, Uncertainty Quantification.

Bachelors' of Engineering, BMS College of Engineering

Bangalore

Sep 2008 — Jun 2012

GPA: 8.87

Topics: Fluid Mechanics, Heat Transfer, Computational Fluid Dynamics.

INTERNSHIPS

Data Scientist, Solid-Link Consulting

Dublin

Aug 2020 — Sep 2020

Focus: Trend analysis of students' admissions in Irish Universities

- · Statistical analysis of admissions into Irish Universities between 2017 2020.
- · Clustering the data points to observe patterns and trends in admissions.

VISA STATUS

Posses valid IG Spouse visa; NO sponsorship necessary.

Ireland